Hey everyone and welcome! Are you ready?
みなさん、こんにちは！準備はいいですか？
Because today we're going on a quest, a question quest.
今日は、質問の冒険に出かけます。
So let's kick things off with a question for you.
さあ、最初の質問です。
Do you like baseball?
野球は好きですか？
See, asking questions in English, it's like having a superpower.
英語で質問するのは、まるで超能力のようです。
And today, we're going to unlock it together.
今日はそれを一緒に解き明かしましょう。
Alright, first up on our quest, it's level 1.
さて、冒険の最初はレベル1です。
And here we're going to meet our heroes, the Dew Crew.
ここで、ヒーローたち、デュークルーに会います。
Okay, so picture this. Your friend says to you, you play the guitar.
友達が「君はギターを弾く」と言ったとしましょう。
That's just a statement, right?
これはただの文ですよね？
But what if you want to ask them if it's true?
でも、これが本当か聞きたいときは？
How do we flip that into a question? It's super easy.
どうやって質問に変えますか？とても簡単です。
It's like a two-step magic recipe.
2ステップの魔法のレシピです。
First, you just pop the magic word do right at the beginning.
まず、魔法の言葉「do」を最初に置きます。
Then step two, you stick a question mark at the end.
次に、最後に疑問符を付けます。
That's literally it. And voila! Do you play the guitar?
これだけです。さあ、Do you play the guitar?
See how simple that was? You've already got the basic pattern down.
簡単でしたね？基本のパターンはもうマスターしました。
Great job!
素晴らしい！
Now this do rule, it works perfectly whenever you're talking about I, you, we, or they.
この「do」のルールは、I、you、we、theyの時に完璧に機能します。
Think of them as a team, right? The do crew.
彼らをチームとして考えてください、デュークルーです。
If one of them is the star of your sentence, do is the word you need.
もしその中の一人が文の主役なら、「do」が必要です。
Okay, ready to try another one? Let's take a look.
次の挑戦に準備はいいですか？見てみましょう。
We've got they speak French. Okay, so they is in our crew.
「they speak French」です。彼らは私たちのクルーにいます。
You know what to do, right? Yes, that's it. Do they speak French?
やるべきことは分かりますよね？そうです、Do they speak French?
See, you just put do at the front,
見てください、doを前に、
a question mark at the end, perfect. You're getting so good at this.
疑問符を後ろに、完璧です。上達していますね。
And just like that, level one is complete. You are a total natural.
これでレベル1はクリアです。あなたは完全に自然です。
But are you ready for a bigger challenge?
でも、もっと大きな挑戦に準備はできていますか？
It's time for the boss level. All right, here we go, boss level.
ボスレベルの時間です。さあ、行きましょう、ボスレベルです。
This is where we learn how to master the word does.
ここで「does」をマスターします。
Now does is a little different, a little trickier,
「does」は少し違って、ちょっと難しいですが、
but super important. Okay, here's our challenge. He sings well.
とても重要です。さて、挑戦です。「He sings well」。
Now look closely, what do you see?
よく見てください、何が見えますか？
That little S on the end of sings, that's our clue.
「sings」の最後の小さなS、それがヒントです。
It's a secret signal telling us, Hey, the rules are about to change.
これは、ルールが変わる合図です。
Yeah, that S is like a special power-up
そう、そのSは特別なパワーアップです。
that the verb gets when we're talking about he, she, or it.
「he」「she」「it」の時に動詞が得るものです。
You might hear your teacher call it the third person singular,
先生が「三人称単数」と呼ぶこともありますが、
but let's just call it the special S rule.
特別なSルールと呼びましょう。
It's the key to this boss fight. So let's think about this.
これがボス戦の鍵です。考えてみましょう。
For they speak, we used do, easy.
「they speak」では「do」を使いました、簡単です。
But now we have he sings with that special S.
でも今は「he sings」で、その特別なSがあります。
So doesn't it make sense that we need a special question word too?
だから、特別な質問の言葉も必要ですよね？
What do you think it is? The hero for this tough job is does.
それは何だと思いますか？この難しい仕事のヒーローは「does」です。
Check it out. Does is really just do with that special S power up
見てください。「does」は「do」にその特別なSパワーが
already built right in. Pretty cool, huh?
すでに組み込まれています。すごいですね？
So the correct question is, does he sing well?
正しい質問は、Does he sing well?
But wait a second, hold on, take a really close look.
でもちょっと待って、よく見てください。
What happened to the S on the verb sings? It disappeared?
「sings」のSはどうなった？消えましたか？
Okay, this right here, this is the boss's number one trick.
これがボスの一番のトリックです。
So many students fall into this trap and say,
多くの学生がこの罠にハマり、
does he sings well, but not you, uh-uh,
「does he sings well」と言ってしまいますが、あなたは違います。
because I'm gonna let you in on the secret
秘密を教えます。
to beat this boss every single time. Okay, listen up,
このボスを毎回倒すための方法です。よく聞いてください。
because this is the most important part.
これが最も重要な部分です。
You only need one S, that's it. That's the whole secret.
必要なのは一つのSだけ、それが全てです。
The word does already has the S. It's carrying all the power.
「does」にはすでにSがあります。それが全ての力を持っています。
So the verb sings doesn't need its S anymore.
だから「sings」はもうSを必要としません。
It goes back to its simple form, sing.
元の形「sing」に戻ります。
Just remember, one S is all you need.
一つのSだけで大丈夫です。
And boom, boss level defeated. That was amazing work.
やった、ボスレベルをクリアしました。素晴らしい仕事です。
All you have to do is remember that one simple trick.
覚えておくべきは、その一つの簡単なコツです。
Does has the S and you will never lose this battle.
「does」にSがついていれば、この戦いには負けません。
Whew, mission complete.
ふぅ、ミッション完了。
Your quest is done and you've got a brand new skill.
あなたのクエストは終わり、新しいスキルを手に入れました。
Let's do a super quick review just to make sure that new superpower
新しいスーパーパワーが定着しているか、 さっと復習しましょう。
is locked in for good. All right, pop quiz time, ready?
さあ、ポップクイズの時間です。準備はいいですか？
The sentence is, I have enough time. Go.
文は「I have enough time」です。どうぞ。
How do you turn that into a question?
これを質問にするにはどうしますか？
And the answer is, do I have enough time? Exactly.
答えは「Do I have enough time?」です。正解です。
I as part of the do crew, so we just use do. Easy peasy.
「I」はdoチームの一員なので、doを使います。簡単ですね。
And this right here, this is your superpower summary.
これがあなたのスーパーパワーの要約です。
Think of it as your secret map for asking questions.
質問をするための秘密の地図だと思ってください。
All you do is, one, check the subject.
やることは、まず主語を確認します。
Two, pick your champion, do or does? That's the whole game plan.
次に、チャンピオンを選びます。doかdoesか？これが全ての計画です。
You guys did such a fantastic job today.
皆さん、今日は素晴らしい仕事をしました。
You've seriously unlocked a new power in your English skills.
本当に英語スキルに新しい力を手に入れました。
And remember, every single time you practice
そして、質問を練習するたびに、
asking a question, you're leveling up. So keep practicing.
レベルアップしています。だから、練習を続けてください。
It's okay to make mistakes, really. That's how we get better.
間違えても大丈夫です。本当に、それが上達の方法です。
So I'm gonna leave you with one last challenge.
最後に一つ挑戦を残します。
Go take this new skill you learned and use it today.
今日学んだ新しいスキルを使ってみてください。
I know you can do it.
あなたならできると信じています。
So what question are you gonna ask in English today?
今日は英語でどんな質問をしますか？